Finding Aid for the Edwin Mims Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Whicher, George F., (1), Nov. 28, 1942; 3
- White, Goodrich C., (6), Feb. 4, Aug. 17, 1950, Jan. 21, July 13, 1953, Apr. 6, July 8, 1954; 3
- White, H. H., (1), Jan. 30, 1941; 3
- White, John E., (3), June 13, 1907, Jan. 25, 1908, 1 undated; 3
- Wiggins, B. L., (3), Nov. 25, 1903, Dec. 14, 1908, Jan. 5, 1909; 3
- Williams, Samuel C. (1), undated; 3
- Wilson, James Southall, (2), Oct. 4, 15, 1926; 3
- Wilson, Louis R., (3), May 15, Aug. 19, 1926, Mar. 31, 1931; 3
- Wilson, Virginia, (lcard), undated; 3
- Wilson, Woodrow, (2), Oct. 26, 1904, Apr. 18, 1906; 3
- Winchester, C. T., (2), Apr. 3, 1906, Oct. 24, 1917; 3
- Woods, C. A., (1), undated; 3
- Woodward, F. G., (2), Feb. 17, 1941, Apr. 25, 1942; 3
- Wreden, Nicholas, (1), May 27, 1954; 3
- Wright, Ernest Hunter, (1), May 27, 1954; 3
- Yarbrough, E. S., (1), May 18, 1934; 3
- Young, Stark, (2), Feb. 16, 1907, Aug. 31, 1934; 3
- Zdanowicz, Casimir, (1), June 8, 1943; 3
- Outgoing Correspondence
  (Xerox copies from two Mims folders in Chancellor's Office files, Vanderbilt University)
  - to Chancellor Kirkland, Jan. 19, 1902
  - to Kirkland, May 10, 1906
  - to Kirkland, Apr. 14, 1926
  - to Kirkland, Mar. 2, 1927
  - to Kirkland, June 10, 1927
  - to Kirkland, Sept. 25, 1929
  - to Kirkland, Jan. 14, 1930
  - to Kirkland, Apr. 9, 1930
  - to Kirkland, May 8, 1930
  - to Kirkland, Oct. 4, 1930
  - to Kirkland (2), Jan. 5, 1931
  - to Kirkland, March-April 1931 (?)
  - to Kirkland (2), Apr. 23, 1931
  - to Kirkland, Apr. 1, 1932
  - to Kirkland, May 5, 1932
  - to Kirkland, Sept. 29, 1932
  - to Kirkland, Oct. 3, 1932
  - to Kirkland, Dec. 21, 1933
  - to Kirkland, Mar. 31, 1934
  - to Kirkland, May 31, 1934
  - to Kirkland, Nov. 30, 1934
  - to Kirkland, Apr. 8, 1935
  - to Kirkland, May 6, 1935
  - to Kirkland, May 8, 1935
  - to Kirkland, Oct. 12, 1935
  - to Kirkland, Mar. 19 (1936?)
  - to Kirkland, Apr. 24, 1937
  - to Kirkland, June 3, 1937
  - to Kirkland, June 4, 1937
  - to Kirkland, June 5, 1937
  - to Kirkland, June 7, 1937
  - to Chancellor Carmichael, Sept. 13, 1937
  - to Carmichael, Sept. 24, 1937
  - to Dean Pomfret, Jan. 7, 1938
  - to Carmichael, Jan. 18, 1938
  - to Carmichael, Nov. 29, 1939
  - to Carmichael, Jan. 16, 1940
  - to Pomfret, Nov. 26, 1940
  - to Carmichael, Oct. 8, 1941
  - to Carmichael, Feb. 8, 1942
  - to Carmichael, Oct. 29, 1942
  - to Carmichael, June 1, 1943
  - to Carmichael, Feb. 2, 1944
  - to Carmichael, Feb. 5, 1945
  - to Chancellor Branscomb, Dec. 19, 1946
  - to Branscomb, Feb. 13, 1947
  - to Branscomb, Feb. 22, 1947
  - to Branscomb, July 9, 1948
  - to Branscomb, Apr. 25, 1949
  - to Branscomb, Sept. 2, 1949
  - to Branscomb, (Sept.-Oct. 1949 )
  - to Branscomb, Nov. 4, 1949
  - to Branscomb, Dec. 13, 1949
  - to Branscomb, Jan. 3, 1951
  - to Branscomb, Oct. 6, 1956
  - to Branscomb, Jan. 13, 1957
  - to Branscomb, Feb. 25, 1957
  - to Dean Rusk, Feb. 19, 1959
  - to Branscomb, May 18, 1959
    (Folder is at end of outgoing correspondence in Box 3)
- Published Writings (articles, pamphlets, etc.)
  - Articles for The Adult Student, 1920-21: "The Responsibility of Citizenship," "The Fundamental Need," "Myself and My Neighbor," "The Blessedness of Work," "Poverty and Wealth," "The Test of the Christian Church," "The Supreme Question for American Patriots," "Guiding Principles for the Settlement of Social Questions." (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - "The Aims of the American College," Vanderbilt University Quarterly, XV, ii (1915). (Address, University of Virginia, February 8, 1915). (Box 7, Folder 4)
    "America and Its Literature'; Public Opinion, May 22, 1936 (address to English Speaking Union).
    "American Ideals in American Literature," University of North Carolina Extension Leaflets, War Information Series, No. 12, 1917.
  - "The Bible Once More," South Atlantic Quarterly, April 1924. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    "Books: Old and New," Christian Advocate, January 23, 1925.
    "Chancellor James H. Kirkland and Vanderbilt University," Southern Association Quarterly, November 1939.
  - "The Contemporary Value of English Classics'; The English Journal (address, National Council of Teachers of English, July 1, 1931). (Box 7, Folder 6)
    "The Correlation of Our Educational System," The Trinity Archive, January 1903 (President's address, North Carolina Teachers' Assembly, June 11, 1902).
    "Does Democracy Exclude Aristocracy?" Sixteenth Annual Educational Conference, University of Kentucky.
    "A Duty and an Opportunity," Christian Advocate, August 20, 1903.
  - "Early Years of the South Atlantic Quarterly," The South Atlantic Quarterly, January 1952 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "An English Teacher's Odyssey'; The Peabody Reflector (lecture, Peabody College, July 23, 1956). (Box 7, Folder 8)
    "The Fight for Idealism," Blue Ridge Voice (address, Y.M.C.A. Student Conference, June 19, 1921).
    "Founders" Day Address, University of the South, October 12, 1948.
  - "A Great American Ambassador" (Walter Hines Page), The Methodist Quarterly Review, January 1923 (review article). (Box 7, Folder 9)
    "A Great American Hellenist" (Professor Gildersleeve), The Methodist Review.
  - "A Handbook for Inter-Racial Committees, Containing Opinions of Representative Southerners and Noteworthy-Acnievements of States and Communities," The Inter-Racial Committee, Atlanta, Georgia, 1920. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    "Has American Literature Had a Square Deal in Great Britain?" The Landmark (speech, Dartmouth House) (ca. 1935-36).
    "Henry Van Dyke, Doctor of Divinity and Master of Many Arts'; The Interior, December 19, 1907.
  - "The Humanities: Past and Present," Southern Association Quarterly, August 1939 (address, Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, March 30, 1939). (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - "The Humanizing of Literature," The English Journal, June 1925. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    "The Importance of the Individual in the Modern World," Vanderbilt Alumnus, June 1944 (Commencement Address, Vanderbilt University, June 5, 1944).
  - "In Social Insight." (Box 7, Folder 11)
    "Independence Day in London," The Landmark (speech, Independence Day Dinner of the Arnerrcan Society inLondon) (ca. 19J5-36).
    "Intellectual and Spiritual America," The Southern Workman (address, Founder's Day, Tuskeggee Institute, April 5, 1927). (incomplete)
    "Is the South Advancing or Retreating?" Southern Conference on Education.
  - "John Maurice Webb, 1847-1916," Nashville, 1946 (address, Webb School Commencement, June 5, 1946). (Box 7, Folder 12)
    "John Morley: The Catholic Man," Southwest Review. (incomplete)
  - "Law and Order in Tennessee: A Story of Inter-Racial Peace," Inter-Racial Committee, Atlanta, Georgia, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    "Learning from Our Neighbors " (incomplete)
    "Leisure and Education," Bulletin of the American Institute of Banking (address before the Pittsbrgh Convention).
  - "The Life and Letters of Charles Eliot Norton," The Methodist Quarterly Review (review article, ca. 1913). (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - "Literature as a National Asset," The Sooner Magazine, April 1930. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    "Lost Leaders," The Southern Workman, March (Founder's Day address, January 29' 1928).
    "Lowell as a Citizen," The South Atlantic Quarterly (incomplete).
  - "Mark Twain: Humorist and Pessimist," The Methodist Quarterly Review (review article, ca. 1912). (Box 7, Folder 16)
    "The Masters of Modern French Criticism," The South Atlantic Quarterly (review article, ca. 1912).
    "Milton in the Modern World."
    "Modern Education and Religion," Christian Education, April 1931. (incomplete)
  - "The New Challenge to Teachers of America," Texas State Teachers' Association (address, Forty-First Annual Meeting). (Box 7, Folder 17)
    "On Books and Reading," The Epworth Era, November-December 1920 (incomplete).
    "Our Silver Anniversary," The Trinity Archive, (address, 25th anniversary of Vanderbilt University).
    "Phillips Brooks's Use of Literature," Christian Advocate, April 25, 1901.
  - "Poetry and the Spiritual Life," The Methodist Review. (Box 7, Folder 18)
    "President Theodore Roosevelt."
  - "Recent Interpretations of American Life, The South Atlantic Quarterly (review article, ca. 1912). (Box 7, Folder 19)
    "Recent Tendencies in American Education," The Peabody Reflector and Alumni News (Sir John Adams Lecture, Institute of Eaucation, University of London, February 24, 1936).
    "Re-Echo from the South" (Survey Graphic, ca. 1926). (Letter to the Editor)
  - "The Renaissance in New England," The South Atlantic Quarterly. (Box 7, Folder 20)
    "A Return to Burns," (address, Burns Club Dinner, St. Louis, January 25, 1941).
    "The Revolt against Chivalry," Readings in Present-Day Writers.
  - "Robert Louis Stevenson" Methodist Review, May 1902 (incomplete). (Box 7, Folder 21)
    "The Sacrificial Element in Life," Blue Ridge Voice,
    "The School Library," North Carolina Journal of Education (Southern Association of Schools and Colleges, Nov. 24, 1893).
  - "A Semi-Centennial Survey of North Carolina's Intellectual Progress," The North Carolina Historical Review. (incomplete). (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - "Six Decades of Southern Education" (address, Sixtieth Anniversary, Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, November 30, 1955). (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - "Some Famous Bird Songs," Vanderbilt Observer. (Box 7, Folder 24)
    "Some Leaves from a Traveler's Note-Book," The Trinity Archive.
    "Some Phases of Literary Criticism," The Methodist Quarterly Review.
  - "The South Pleads for Just Criticism, "The Independent, November 20, 1926. (Box 7, Folder 25)
    "Stevenson's Life and Works (Introduction)."
    "Thomas Nelson Page." (incomplete)
  - "Travel," Junior-Senior High School Clearing House, May 1932. (Box 7, Folder 26)
    "Trinity College," American Methodist Magazine, Jannary 1901.
    "Vanderbilt University," The Outlook, October 27, 1900. (incomplete)
  - "Walter Hines Page: Friend of the South," The South Atlantic Quarterly, April 1919 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    "The War and Higher Education," Association of American Colleges Bulletin, (address, Inauguration of President, Florida State College for Women, February 20-21, 1942). (incomplete)
    "What Should Be Done by Colleges and Universities for the Religious Training of Students," Southern Educational Review. (incomplete)
  - "Woodrow Wilson: The Happy Warrior," The Methodist Quarterly Review, April 1924. (Box 7, Folder 28)
    "The Work and Influence of the College Professor outside the Class Room," Proceedings Southern States Association.
  - Book reviews: (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Published writings, untitled and incomplete. (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Subject Entries
  - Americanism
  - American Literature - Southern states
  - Duke University, Durham
  - General Education Board
  - Internationalism
  - James Hampton Kirkland
  - Lee, Robert E.
  - Race Relations
  - The South ( U. S. )
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools
  - Southern Education Association
  - Vanderbilt University, Nashville
  - ‘world War, 1914-1918
- Chronologocal Entries
  - 1890-1899
  - 1900-1909
  - 1920-1929
  - 1930-1939
  - 1940-1949
  - For name entries, see Index of Incoming Correspondence in the Register
    This is a chronological index of Edwin Mims' letters to Clara (Puryear) Mims. The number in parentheses following the year refers to the box in which this correspondence is to be found. The place name given in parentheses following the day and month, is the place from which the letter was sent, and includes all letters between semi-colons.
- 1892 (11) - June 28, July 13, July 27, Aug. 3, aug. 15, Aug.25, Oct. 1, Oct. 7, Nov. 14, Nov. 26. (Box 11)
- 1893 (11) - Jan.8, Jan. 20, Mar. 5, Jun. 23, July 7, July 28, Aug. 24, Sept. 10, Sept. 17, Oct.1, Dec. 8. (Box 11)
- 1894 (11) - Jan. 9, Mar.25, Apr. 15, May 13, May 30, June 10, June 25, July 5, July 12, July 20, Aug. 2, Aug. 16, Aug. 27, Sept. 8, Sept. 19, Oct. 14, Nov. 4, Dec.24. (Box 11)
- 1895 (11) - Jan. 6, Jan. 15, Feb. 3, Mar. 3, Apr. 2, Apr. 16, June 29, July 20, July 28, Aug. 15, Aug. 29, Sept. 23, Oct. 6, Oct. 11, Oct. 20, Nov. 15, Dec.15. (Box 11)
- 1896 (11) - Jan.1, Jan.2, Jan. 5, Jan. 9, Jan. 14, Jan.23, Jan. 28, Jan. 31, Feb. 1, Feb.7 (2), Feb.18, Feb. 23, Feb. 28, Mar. 1, Mar.4, Mar. 10, Mar. 15, Mar. 18, Mar. 27, Apr. 4, Apr. 13, Apr. 17, Apr. 23, May 7, May 17, May 20, May 26 1 (2), June 1, June 7, July 9, July 16, July 17, July 21, July 25, July 27, Aug. 3, Aug. 4, Aug. 9, Aug. 10, Aug. 12, Aug. 14, Aug. 15, Aug. 19 (2), Aug. 23, Aug. 25, Aug. 28, Aug. 30. (Box 11)
- 1896 (12) - Sept. 2, Sept. 4, Sept. 6, Sept. 9, Sept. 12, Sept. 13, Sept. 15, Sept. 19, Sept. 20, Sept. 23, Sept. 26, Sept. 27, Sept. 30, Oct. 3, Oct.4, Oct. 7, Oct. 9, Oct. 11, Oct.14, Oct. 16, Oct. 18, Oct. 20, Oct. 22, Oct. 25, Oct. 28, Oct. 29, Nov. 1, Nov. 8, Nov. 11, Nov. 12, Nov.15, Nov. 19, n.d., Nov. 22, Nov. 25, Nov. 29, Dec. 1, Dec. 3, Dec. 6, Dec.11, Dec. 14, Dec. 19, Dec. 20, Dec.21, Dec. 22, Dec. 24, Dec. 26, Dec. 27, Dec. 28, Dec. 30, Dec. 31, n.d. ,. (Box 12)
- 1897 (12) - Jan. 3, Jan.6, Jan. 7, Jan.10, Jan. 14, Jan. 21, Jan. 24, Jan. 28, Feb. 3, Feb.7, Feb. 11, Feb.15, Feb. 16, Feb. 19, Feb. 21, Feb.25, Mar. 1, Mar. 5, Mar.8, Mar. 14, Mar. 19, Mar. 26, Apr.1, Apr. 3, Apr. 6 (2), Apr. 7, Apr. 9, Apr. 10, Apr. 11, Apr.13, Apr. 15, Apr. 18, Apr. 20, Apr. 25, Apr.28, Apr. 29, May 2, May 4, May 6, May 9, May 11, May 14, May 16, May 18, May 21, May 23, May 26, May 27, May 30, June 3, June 6, June 8, June 9, June 12, June 13, June 15, June 18, June 20, June 22, June 27, June 30. (Box 12)
- 1897 (13) - July 4, July 8, July 11, July 14, July 17, July 19, July 28, July 29, July 31, Aug. 2, Aug. 4, Aug. 6, Aug. 8, Aug. 10, Aug. 11, Aug. 12, Aug. 14, Aug. 16, Aug. 18, Aug. 20, Aug. 21, Aug. 24, Aug. 28, Sept. 6, Sept. 8, Sept. 9, Sept. 11, Sept. 12, Sept. 15, ept. 16, Sept. 18, Sept. 21, Sept. 24, Sept. 27, Sept. 29, Oct. 2, Oct. 3, Oct. 5, Oct.9, Oct. 12, Oct. 15, Oct. 20, Oct. 23, Oct. 24, Oct. 27, Nov. 2, Nov. 3, Nov. 6, Nov. 11, Nov. 14, Nov.17, Nov. 20, Nov. 22, Nov. 24, Nov. 25, Nov. 28, Dec. 3, Dec. 4, Dec. 6, Dec. 11, Dec.12, Dec. 15, Dec.21, Dec. 22, Dec. 23, Dec. 25, Dec. 27, Dec. 29. (Box 12)
- 1898 (13) - Jan. 3, Jan. 4, Jan.5, Jan. 6, Jan. 7, Jan.10 (2), Jan. 13, Jan. 15, Jan.17, Jan. 18, Jan. 20, Jan. 22, Jan. 24, Jan. 25, Jan. 30, Feb. 2, Feb.7, Feb. 9, Feb. 12, Feb. 16, Feb. 19. (2), Feb. 21, Feb. 25, Feb. 26, Feb. 28, Mar. 3, Mar. 7, Mar. 9, Mar. 12, Mar. 14, Mar. 15, Mar. 18, Mar. 20, Mar. 21, Mar. 22, Mar. 23, Mar. 24, Mar. 29, Mar. 30, Mar. 31, Apr. 5, Apr. 6, Apr. 7, Apr.8, Apr. 11, Apr.12 (2), Apr. 19, Apr. 20, Apr. 21, Apr.23, Apr. 24 (2), Apr. 27, Apr. 28, May 3, May 4, May 6, May 7, May 12, May 16, May 18 (2), May 21, May 22, May 24, May 25, May 27, May 30, June 1, June 2, June 4, June 5, June 8, June 10, June 11, June 13, June 14, June 16, June 18, June 20, June 21, June 23, June 24, June 25, June 26, Aug. 28, Aug. 30, Aug. 31. (Box 12)
- 1899 (13) - Mar. 1, Mar. 11, Mar. 31. (Box 12)
- 1899 (14) - Apr. 1, Apr. 2, Apr. 3, Apr. 4, Apr. 8, Apr. 10, Apr. 11, Apr. 13, Apr. 16, Apr.17, Apr. 18, Apr. 19, Apr.20, Apr.21, n.d., Apr. 22, Apr. 23, Apr. 24, Apr. 25, Apr. 27, Apr. 29 (2), Apr. 30, May 1, May 5, May 6, May 7, May 9, May 10(2), May 13, May 14, May 16, May 18, May 21, May 24, May 25, May 27, May 30, May 31, June 5 (2), June 6, May 20 (Durham, N.C.). (Box 14)
- 1900 (14) - June 15 (Greensboro, N.C.). (Box 14)
- 1905 (14) - n.d. (2), May 7, May 19, June (Durham, N.C.). (Box 14)
- 1908 (14) - June 23, June 24 (New Haven); June 25, June 27 (New York); June 28 (Princeton); July 2, July 4, July 9, July 11, July 14, July 16, July 17, July 19, July 29, n.d. (3)(Charlottesville). (Box 14)
- 1909 (14) - June 14, June 17 (Durham); June 18, June 20, June 25 (2), July 1, July 7, July 10, July 13, July 17, July 18, July 23, July 24, July 25, July 27, n.d. (4) (Charlottesville); Aug. 4 (2) (Blanche, N.C.); Aug. 10 (Danville, Va.); Aug. 12,(Blanche, N.C.). (Box 14)
- 1910 (14) - Apr. 16, n.d. (Geneva); n.d. (Milan); Apr19 (:Pisa); Apr. 20, Apr. 26, Apr. 27, n.d. (2) ( e); May 3, May 5, May 7, May 10, May 13, May 15 (Florence); n.d. (3)(Venice); May 27 (Innsbruck). (Box 14)
- 1911 (14) - Aug. 22 (Monteagle, Tn.). (Box 14)
- 1912 (14) - June 22, June 25, June 27, June 28, June 29, July 13, July 30, n.d. (9) (Chapel Hill, N.C.); Oct. 24, Oct. 28, Nov. 30, n.d. (7)(Nashville). (Box 14)
- 1913 (14) - June 28 (Greensboro, N.C.); July 3, July 8, July 16 (2), July 26, n.d. (4) (Baltimore). (Box 14)
- 1914 (14) - Aug. 21 (Nashville) (Box 14)
- 1916 (14) - Aug. 30 (Nashville) (Box 14)
- 1919 (14) - Aug. 25 (Nashville) (Box 14)
- 1922 (14) - July 4 (Nashville); Aug. 4, n.d. (2), Aug. 8, Aug. 22, n.d. (4) (Charlottesville); Aug. 26 (Woodberry Forest, Va.). (Box 14)
- 1923 (14) - Mar. 29, Mar. 30, n.d. (10) (Pasadena); April 6, April 21 (Pomona); May 1, May 5, n.d. (5) (Pasadena); Oct. 26 (Detroit). (Box 14)
- 1924 (14) - June 28, n.d. (Los Angeles). (Box 14)
- 1926 (14) - July 8, n.d. (2) (Chautauqua, N.Y.). (Box 14)
- 1928 (14) - Aug. 4, Aug. 23, Aug. 25, n.d. (5)(Saratoga Springs, N.Y.). (Box 14)
- 1934 (14) - Aug. (Los Angeles) (Box 14)
- 1936 (14) (letters from the British Isles); -Jan. 30, Mar. 15, Mar. 30, Apr.4, Apr. 5, Apr. 15 (London); May 4, May 19, May 27, n.d. (2)(Exeter); Sept. 22, Sept. 30, n.d. (20) (London); n.d. (4) (St. Andrews, Fife); n.d. (Edinburgh); n.d. (2) (Herefordshire.); n.d. (5)(Dublin). (Box 14)
- 1936 (14) (letters from Continental Europe);- July 20 (Geneva); July 24 (Vienna); July 29 (Berlin); Aug. 1 (Warsaw); Aug. 4, Aug. 11 (Moscow). (Box 14)
- 1942 (14) - July 8 (Duke University?); Oct. 4, n.d. (Greenwich, Conn.); Nov.18 (Haverford, Pa.); Nov. 21 (Lewisburg, Pa.). (Box 14)
- 1943 (14) - Feb. 14, n.d. (Macon, Ga.); Feb. 20 (Jacksonville, Fla). (Box 14)
- 1945 (14) - Feb.26 (Mount Vernon, Iowa); Mar. 1 (St. Louis, Mo.); n.d; Mar.6 (Jacksonville, Ill.); Apr.16 (Jackson, Miss.); June 14, June 24, June 27, July 1, n.d. (Salt Lake City); Aug. 6 (Portland, Ore.); aug. 10, n.d.; Aug. 15 (Billings, Mont.); Aug. 24 (Salt Lake City); Sept. 3, Sept. 5 (Los Angeles): (Box 14)
- 1946 (14) - July 7 (Provo, Utah); Oct. 12, Oct. 21 (Nashville, Tn.); Oct. 26 (Chicago); Oct. 28 (St. Paul); Dec. 4 (Atlanta); Dec. 5, Dec.7, Dec. 9, Dec. 11, Dec. 13 (Raleigh, N.C.); Dec. 18, Dec. 25 (2), Dec. 31, n.d. (Winter Park, Fla.). (Box 14)
- 1947 (15) - Jan. 15, Jan.16, Jan. 17 (Winter Park, Fla.); Jan. 21 (Atlanta); Jan. 23, Feb.2, Feb.5, Feb. 8, Feb. 12, Feb. 16, Feb. 19 (?), Mar. 1, Mar. 12 (Winter Park, Fla.); Mar. 21 (St. Augustine); n.d. (4)(Winter Park, Fla.). (Box 15)
- 1948 (15) - Feb. 17, Feb.21, n.d. (3) (DeLand, Fla.); Feb.24, Mar. 3, Mar. 6 (Winter Park, Fla.); Sept. 10 (New York). (Box 15)
- 1949 (15) - Jan. 29 (Lakeland, Fla.); Feb. 17, Feb. 19, Feb. 25 (Winter Park, Fla.); July 24 (Santa Fe, N.M.); Nov.?(Macon, Ga.). (Box 15)
- 1950(15) - Feb. 27, March 2, March 3 (Winter Park); June 7 (Nashville); June 27, July 3 (Los ngeles); Sept. 30 (Greenwich, Conn); Oct. 2 (Boston); Oct. 28, Oct. 31, Nov. 11, Nov. 20, Nov. 23, June 15, Nov. 29, Dec. 2, Dec. 2, Dec. 6, Dec. 9, Dec. 12 (?) (New York). (Box 15)
- 1951 (15) - Jan. 2, Jan. 2, Jan. 12, n.d. (4) (New York). (Box 15)
- 1952 (15) - Nov. 2 (Atlanta). (Box 15)
- 1958 (15) - Aug. 20 (Asheville, N.C.). (Box 15)
- Undated (Nashville) - 11 (Box 15) (Box 15)
- Undated (California) - 15 (Box 15)
- Undated letters to C.P.M. - 31 + 4 fragments (Box 15)
- Letters to C.P.M. from others - # in parentheses is total #'of letters from that person.
- Janan, Rose E., (1), Aug.16, 1896
- Locke, Wills., (1), July 15, 1892
- Mims, Edwin, Jr., (2), Jan. 19, 1912, n.d. (fragment)
- Robins, Jas. A., (3), Mar. 21, June 18, July 28, 1898
- 1 illegible, July 10, 1895
- Letters to E.M. from C.P.M.
- 1895 - Jan. 3 (Paris)
- 1925 - March 13
- 1926 - June 28
- Correspondence - Outgoing
  - To the honorable Faculty of Vanderbilt University., 1890 - Oct. 10 (Box 15)
  - Mr. Puryear; Mar. 21, Mrs. Puryear., 1898 - Mar. 5 (Box 15)
  - Elanor., 1907- n.d (Box 15)
  - 1909 - Aug. 10, Colonel; Sept.10, Elanor; Oct.29, "Colonel"; Nov. 22, Elanor. (Box 15)
  - 1910 - Feb. 11, Elise; Mar. 3, Momma (Mrs. A.J. Mims); Mar. 18, Elise; April 19, Mamma; April 2, Mamma. (Box 15)
  - Mr. Southgate., 1912 - Feb. 4 (Box 15)
  - Mr. Southgate, 1914 - Nov. 9 (Box 15)
  - "Colonel"., 1916 - Jan. 1 (Box 15)
  - Chancellor Kirkland., 1917 - Mar. 2 (Box 15)
  - 1918 - Mar. 18, Elanor; Oct. 13, Elanor. (Box 15)
  - Donald., 1923 - Sept. 5 (Box 15)
  - 1926 - Apr. 8, Mr. Nichols; July 16, Mamma,(Mrs. A.J. Mims). (Box 15)
  - 1927 - Jan. 1, Mr. Nichols; Oct. 24, Payne. (Box 15)
  - Managing Editor, The World, New York City., 1928 - Mar.7 (Box 15)
  - Mr. Darrow., 1929 - Dec. 1 (Box 15)
  - Mrs. Harris., 1931 - Mar. 28 (Box 15)
  - Mr. Edward K. Graham., 1933 - Jan. 18 (Box 15)
  - Mr. Haskell, Carnegie Endowment for International Peace., 1934 - Oct. 9 (Box 15)
  - Mr. Haskell., 1935 - Dec. 10 (Box 15)
  - 1936 - Jan. 29, Dr. Butler; Jan.29, Mr. Haskell; Mar. 5, Mr. Haskell; April 24, Mr. Haskell. (Box 15)
  - 1937 - June 4 (Box 15)
  - (Letters bearing on the English Department at Vanderbilt) (Box 15)
  - 1944 - Nov. 4, "Letter to Chancellor Carmichael"; Nov. 4, Chancellor Carmichael. (Box 15)
  - Mrs. Louise Cowan (two copies), 1954 - Aug. 18 (Box 15)
  - 1955 - Feb. 26, Professor Everett; Feb. 26, Mr. Binkley; Feb. 26, Dean (Box 15)
  - Shanks; Feb. 26, Edgar Rand; Feb.26, Mr. Geiger; Feb. 26, Dean Ward. (Box 15)
  - Mr. Hodding Carter., 1959 - Feb. 13 (Box 15)
  - Edwin Mims, Jr.; Mr. Southgate; Mr. Latham; and 2 letters without addressees., n.d. (Box 15)
- Correspondence - Incoming
  This ia a name index of the correspondents of Edwin Mims. The number in parentheses following each name denotes the total number of letters from that person in the collection; The dates are for the time of the letters; The last number given refers to the box in which the correspondence is found.
  - A
    - Adams, Agnes, (1), Feb. 5, 1941; 15 (Box 15)
    - Adams, Lawrence, (1), Apr. 1, 1914; 15 (Box 15)
    - Aiken, Newton, (1), Sept. 5, 1958; 15 (Box 15)
    - Alderman, Edwin, (5), Nov. 5, 1907, Oct. 10, 1908, May 28, 1912, Feb. 22, 1915, Mar. 4, 1918; 15 (Box 15)
    - Alexander, Henry, (1), Christmas, 1958; 15 (Box 15)
    - Alston, Wallace M., (2), May 3, 1956, Apr. 2, 1959; 15 (Box 15)
    - Aycock, G.B., (2), Nov. 6, 1903, Feb. 4, 1905; 15 (Box 15)
  - B
    - Bard, Howard B., (1), Apr. 23, 1923; 15 (Box 15)
    - Bardeleben, Mary D., (1), n.d.; 15 (Box 15)
    - Baskerville, Janie McV., (1), Apr. 10, 1900; 15 (Box 15)
    - Baskerville, W.M., (1), June 14, 1898; 15 (Box 15)
    - Beatty, Richmond C., (1), July 17, 1942; 15 (Box 15)
    - Bethurum, Dorothy, (1), July 3, 1954; 15 (Box 15)
    - Bierck, John E., (1), Mar. 17, 1959; 15 (Box 15)
    - Biggs, Margie, (1), Jan. 26, 1958; 15 (Box 15)
    - Blair, D.H., (1), Nov. 6, 1928; 15 (Box 15)
    - Blair, Eve, (1), May 8, 1959; 15 (Box 15)
    - Bradbury, John, (1), June 27, 1958; 15 (Box 15)
    - Braden, Chas. S., (2), May 4, 1944, Mar. 30, 1948; 15 (Box 15)
    - Branscomb, Harvie, (3), Dec. 21, 1949, Jan. 31, 1950, Jan. 17, 1957; 15 (Box 15)
    - Briggs, L.B.R., (1), Feb. 21, 1903; 15 (Box 15)
    - Bryant, J. Allen, (1), Mar. 22, 1959; 15 (Box 15)
    - Bryson, Fred, (1), Oct. 15, 1944; 15 (Box 15)
    - Butler, Nicholas Murray, (2), Aug. 21, 1937, Dec. 7, 1937; 15 (Box 15)
  - C
    - Cadman, Rev. S. Parkes, (1), May 14, 1926; 15 (Box 15)
    - Cannon, Bill, (1), Mar. 30, 1956; 15 (Box 15)
    - Carmichael, O.C., (2), Feb. 5, 1942, Dec. 31, 1957; 15 (Box 15)
    - Carpenter, Margaret, (1), May 15, 1959; 15 (Box 15)
    - Cason, Charles, (3), Mar. 18, 1926, Feb. 23, 1941, Feb. 24, 1941; 15 (Box 15)